

Mohammad Khair AbuShanab Electrical Engineer

≥ M.mk.58@hotmail.com

+962-795816660

LinkedIn: @Mohammad-AS

I am an Engineering graduate with 6 months of experience in Energy distribution, with a solid foundation in electronics and the fundamentals of communications, through working on previous projects, I have developed my research and problem solving skills.

Experience

JEPCO Energy distribution Internship

Sep 2021 - May 2022

- Conducted and revised multiple energy distribution cases at the study and planning department.
- Examined the process of automating a new or old distribution station at the automation department and in accordance with communication and SCADA departments.

Shared AI training

Aug 2021 - Oct 2022

· Computer vision training part of a funded project, this training was aimed to teach the basics of computer vision to solve the task at hand.

IEEE Engineering bootcamp

June 2022 - July 2022

· Part of a engineering medicine society (EMS) contest, a technical bootcamp aimed to elevate the participants technical skills.

Projects

JODDB & KAFD

feb 2021 - May 2022

• JODDB endorsed, KAFD funded graduation project, novel shaped conical coil charging for autonomous drones.

IEEE EMS chapter

June 2022- Jul 2022

 development and optimizing of an AI model for classifying EEG scans, to accurately differentiate and provide a clear diagnosis for stroke and epilepsy patients without the help of a professional.

Pepsico Arab youth hackathon

Sep 2022- Oct 2022

• Hackathon participation, with a roof cleaning drone project submission.

Education

Islamic Educational College

· Elementary through High school education

The Hashemite University

- Major in Electrical Engineer, submajor in communication and electronics
- Bachelor of Engineering, 2.7 GPA

■ Software, Hardware, and Professional Skills

- MS Office
- Ansys Maxwell Electronics
- AutoCad
- google colab
- MATLAB

- Arduino
- Raspberry Pi
- Jetson Nano
- Power Electronics
- Problem Solving
- Analytical and Research Skills
- Coding(Python, Javascript, C++)
- Computer skills